## **MATTHEW O'LEARY**

mattoleary-product-designer.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/matt-oleary | mattosurf@gmail.com

## **Professional Summary**

Skilled Senior UX Designer with over 10 years of experience providing user-centered experience and interface design in a number of industries. Extensive experience in all aspects of UX and Product Design including visual design for native, web and mobile applications, user testing and research, asset and spec creation, and team leadership. Continually exceeds expectations by building valuable relationships and works well with people at all levels of an organization, including stakeholders, management, team members, and clients.

#### Skills

- User-centered experience & interaction design
- Design management
- Rapid/iterative design & prototyping
- Usability testing & research
- Quantitative and qualitative data analysis
- Accessible & inclusive design
- UI & visual design
- Design systems/ Systems thinking
- Product copy
- Information architecture
- Typography & layout expertise
- User flows & wireframes
- Excellent verbal & written communication

# **Work History**

### **Senior UX Designer | 2018 to Current**

Axway – Santa Clara, CA

- Leading UX, visual, and information design for mobile and SAAS products, promoting design thinking across the company while engaging with product teams throughout definition, research, analysis and synthesis.
- Product design for web, tablet, and Android or iOS phone applications, writing micro-copy and calls-to-action, creating assets and delivering to developers along with clear specifications.
- Transforming product requirements and stories into user flows via discussions, whiteboarding, or sketching, wireframing, and quick prototyping.
- Established usability testing program (both moderated and unmoderated) to ensure that solutions meet client and end user needs and expectations.
- Defining research goals and identifying target users by working cross-functionally with design, product management, content strategy, engineering and marketing to design clean, intuitive, and innovative interfaces.
- Manage four other UX and Interaction Designers.

#### Senior UX Designer | 2014 to 2018

Accellion – Palo Alto, CA

- Guided the entirety of the design process through its completion by presenting UX design solutions to stakeholders and working alongside developers to ensure accurate implementation.
- Led a team of designers and coached the team through reviews and feedback, supporting their UX/UI growth while raising the capacity, skills, and quality of user-centered design on the team.
- Applied user flow and mapped out pathways an individual would take in a website or
  platform as well as created affinity diagrams at any time during the pre-design process,
  successfully performing task analyses.
- Led user testing with customers and iterated based on feedback, leading accessibility audits and driving necessary changes for 508 compliance, creating assets and delivering final assets to developers along with clear specifications.
- Interviewed target audiences and recorded their responses to be archived and used later in the process as well as developed personas and created profiles for particular users based on characteristics.
- Manage one other Interaction Designer.

#### **Creative Lead | 2011 to 2014**

FastPencil - Campbell, CA

- Developed overall flow, interactions, and visual design of FastPencil 2.0 including a complete refresh of the cloud-based publishing platform and created HTML prototypes that were used to successfully sell the brandable publishing platform.
- Art-directed freelance designers and illustrators, designing book covers for authors and templates for automatic book creation as well as wrote support documentation for FastPencil 2.0.
- Critiqued in-progress design work, evaluating the priority and effectiveness of solutions while providing and encouraging feedback from the team and other designers, studying analytics to understand user behavior.
- Designed marketing communications, landing pages, email campaigns, or author web pages, partnering with the creative team and developers to maintain a cohesive design and experience throughout product development, providing expertise and mentorship.
- Directed and motivated teams of art directors, illustrators, and copywriters, leading brainstorming or creative sessions to generate ideas as well as revising content or presentations, approving or rejecting ideas, and providing feedback to the team.

#### **Technical Skills**

CSS, HTML, Frameworks (11ty), Foundation, Bootstrap, GitHub, WordPress, Microsoft Office

# **Training & Education**

- Emotional Design Psychology & Neuroscience Course with Brian Cugelman
- Cooper U's Visual Interface Design: Goal-directed Visual Design Process

- Fine Arts studies including Scientific Illustration, Life Drawing, Painting, and Art History at University of California, Santa Cruz
- Graphic Design Department Coursework in Design, Color Theory, Airbrush, Silkscreen, 2- and 3-D Fundamentals, and Typography at San Jose State University
- Production Techniques for the Graphic Artist Series, Advanced Photoshop Composition and Color Theory and Expression Workshops at University of California, Santa Cruz Extension
- Breakthrough Thinking
- Frontline Management

## Links

Portfolio: https://mattoleary-product-designer.netlify.app

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-oleary

Email: http://mailto:mattosurf@gmail.com

References available upon request